DAKOTA NICHOLS

Nashville, Tennessee | dakotachantz@gmail.com | (615) 415-1709 | dakotachantz.com

Summary

Full Stack Application Developer. Primary experience within the realms of React/Redux, Node, all contained within AWS. Lover of crafting creative software solutions. Believer that teamwork is the foundation of our future, prosperous workforce.

Skills

- React/Redux
- JavaScript
- AWS Services
- NodeJS

- Version Control w/Git
- Problem-Solver
- Teamwork
- RESTful API's

- Docker
- Testing/Debugging
- HTML/CSS
 - Bootstrap/Materialize

Experience

Application Developer - XSOLIS | Nashville, TN Dec 2017 - Current

- Rewrote React/Redux Front-End of internal app to better utilize component based architecture
- Redesigned UI of internal application to improve UX, consistency, and usability
- Developed scripts for build, deployment, and related tasks for Docker
- Managed Docker container inside of AWS ECS on a large EC2 instance
- Assisted in development and maintenance of new APIs for integration with internal applications
- Configured Auth0 to handle authentication using SSO via ADFS
- Developed PowerShell scripts to be deployed on SQL Server instances to upload backup files created by a micro service to \$3
- Configured S3 buckets with various life cycle policies to archive infrequently accessed data to storage classes based on requirement
- Created library of Higher Order Components to be utilized throughout application
- Assisted in developing JIRA workflows and schemes
- Worked closely with the project management team to define specifications to help ensure project acceptance

Full Stack Fundamentals w/React Specialization - The Iron Yard | Nashville, TN Jul 2017 - Oct 2017

Rigorous 12-week full stack fundamentals coding bootcamp specializing in highly focused, immersive training centered on language fluency, object-oriented programming, and project-based learning. Specialization in React framework.

- **Homeless Helper** | Application created to provide local resources for the homeless. Built with React, Google Maps API, Open Data API, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.
 - o Code: <u>github.com/dakotachantz/homeless-helper</u>
 - o Live Site: homelesshelper.co/

In House Marketing Supervisor - Wyndham Vacation Ownership | Nashville, TN Oct 2015 – Jul 2017

- Led a team of 24 in house marketers to exceed budgeted leads at site level
- Launched Online Manifest (OLM) with corporate development team; a web application used to book prospective leads for the sales department
- Created training guides for OLM and new onboarding training for the local site
- Developed new marketing strategies and evaluated incoming arrival flow with sales partners and regional training team to write action plans to exceed specific objectives
- Instill a culture of success by engaging peer to peer empowerment and mentality of "1 Team 1 Dream"

Education

Truckee Meadows Community College (TMCC) | Reno, NV Jan 2013 – Jan 2015 Related Coursework: Information Systems, Computer Science, Web Development